(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.1",
"generated_at": "2026-08-08T23:27:34.312419",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.6-flash",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
ビターチョコデコレーション
[Bitter Choco Decoration]
人を過度に信じないように
So I don't trust people excessively,
愛さないように 期待しないように
so I don't love, so I don't expect anything.
かと言って角が立たないように
Even so, to keep from causing friction,
気取らぬように 目立たぬように
without being pretentious, without standing out.
誰一人傷つけぬように
So I don't hurt a single person,
虐めぬように 殺さぬように
so I don't bully, so I don't kill.
かと言って偽善がバレないように
Even so, to keep my hypocrisy from being exposed,
威張らないように
without acting arrogant.
軽いジョークやリップサービスも忘れぬように
Never forgetting light jokes and lip service,
どんな時も笑って愛嬌振りまくように
always smiling and lavishing charm.
ビターチョコデコレーション
Bitter choco decoration,
とかく言わずにたんと召し上がれ
eat up plenty without saying a word.
ビターチョコデコレーション
Bitter choco decoration,
食わず嫌いはちゃんと直さなきゃ
you must fix your prejudice without trying.
頭空っぽその後に残る心が本物なら
If the heart left behind after emptying your head is genuine,
きっと君だって同じ事
surely you are the same.
ところで一つ伺いますが...
By the way, I have one question...
やっぱいや
Never mind.
人に過度に
To not trust people...
信じないように
...a bit too much,
愛さないように
to not love them,
期待しないように
to not expect anything,
かと言って
but even so,
角が立たないように
to not cause trouble,
気取らぬように
to not put on airs,
目立たぬように
to not stand out,
誰一人
to not hurt...
傷つけぬように
...a single person,
いじめぬように
to not bully,
殺さぬように
to not kill,
かと言って
but even so,
偽善がバレないように
to not let hypocrisy show,
威張らないように
to not act grand,
軽いジョークやリップサービスも
and to never forget small jokes...
忘れぬように
...and lip service,
どんな時も笑って
to laugh at all times...
愛嬌振りまくように
...and shower everyone with charm.
ビターチョコデコレーション
Bitter choco decoration,
ともなく言わずにたんとお召し上がれ
without a word, eat it all up.
ビターチョコデコレーション
Bitter choco decoration,
食わず嫌いはちゃんと直さなきゃ
you gotta fix your picky eating.
頭空っぽ
Empty your head,
その後に残る心が本物なら
and if what remains in your heart is real,
きっと君だって
surely you too...
相同事
...are the same.
ところで一つ伺いますが
"By the way, let me ask you one thing..."
先日何処かで...
"The other day, somewhere..."
やっぱいいや
"...actually, never mind."
無駄に自我を晒さぬように
To not expose your ego needlessly,
話さぬように分からぬように
to not speak, to remain unknown,
でも絶対口を閉ざさぬように
but never to keep completely silent,
笑わすより笑われるように
to be laughed at rather than to make laugh,
人をちゃんと敬うように
to properly respect others,
崇めるように称えるように
to revere them, to praise them,
でも決して嫌味にならないように
but never to sound sarcastic,
ふざけないように
to not mess around.
集団参加の終身刑
Life sentence of group participation,
またへーこらへーこら言っちゃって
bowing and scraping yet again.
あれっ 前髪超絶最高ジャン
"Huh? Your bangs are ridiculously awesome!"
とかどうでもいいのに言っちゃって
Saying things like that even when you don't care at all.
毎朝毎晩もう限界
Every morning and night, I'm at my limit.
宗教的社会の集団リンチ
Group lynching in a religious society.
でも決して発狂しないように
But never let yourself go crazy.
ビターチョコデコレーション
Bitter choco decoration,
時に孤独な愛は君を汚す
sometimes lonely love taints you.
ビターチョコデコレーション
Bitter choco decoration,
立つ鳥の後きっと糞のアート
a departing bird surely leaves behind art of dung.
初めはあんな大層な大言壮語を並べたが
At first, I lined up such grand, boastful words,
嫌よ嫌よも好きのうち
but "no, no" actually means "yes".
いやはやしかし今日が初めてで
"My, my, but today being my first time..."
こんなとはね 君センスあるよ
"...doing this, you really got talent!"
恋する季節にビターチョコデコレーション
Bitter choco decoration in the season of love,
恋する気持ちでビターチョコデコレーション
bitter choco decoration with feelings of love.
F.U.C.K.Y.O.U
ビターチョコデコレーション
Bitter choco decoration,
皆が望む理想に憧れて
longing for the ideal everyone wants.
ビターチョコデコレーション
Bitter choco decoration,
僕の心を殺して土に埋め
kill my heart and bury it in the dirt.
ビターチョコデコレーション
Bitter choco decoration,
僕はおとなにやっと見習ったよママ
I finally learned to act like an adult, Mom.
明日の一切合切の先を
Everything that lies ahead tomorrow...
地獄は続くどこまでも
...hell continues on forever.
だからずっと今だけを
So right now, just focus on this moment...
今度モグラの殺す気持ちのままで
...with the mindset of killing moles,
一歩も譲らずにやっていこうぜ
without backing down a single step, let's keep going.
思い出した方がいいさあのあの時の
You'd better remember the awkwardness...
気まずさも
...of back then too.
やっぱいいや
Never mind.
Actually, never mind.
サイコロ...
A die...
5が出た！
I rolled a 5!
ん？何これ？
Hm? What's this?
椅子？
A chair?
1, 2, 1!
One, two, one!
Deal with the devil
アップダウンは世の常
Ups and downs are the way of the world.
クズ引いたって動じない
Even drawing a bad hand won't shake me.
肝心なのは Strong な Mind
What matters is a strong mind.
出し抜いて Survive
Outsmart them and survive.
行きつく先は Heaven or hell
Where we end up is heaven or hell.
この世界のルール
In the rules of this world,
たった一つ 勝者こそが正義
there's only one: the winner is justice.
女は度胸
A woman needs guts,
焦れさせるのアイツを
keeping him on edge.
やれること なんだってやる
Whatever can be done, I'll do it all.
あたしは賭け狂いのクイーン
I'm the gambling-obsessed queen.
お見通しさ You doubt me
"I see right through you," you doubt me.
読み切って レッツ Showdown
Reading your hand, let's showdown!
Deal with the devil
見透かして あたしのものにする
Seeing through you, I'll make you mine,
あなたの髪の一本まで全部
down to every single strand of your hair.
A million dollars I'd say raise
震えてるわよ 坊や
You're trembling, boy.
降ろさせはしないわ
I won't let you fold!
Deal with the devil
興奮 たまらないわ スリル
Excitement... this thrill is irresistible!
誰にも触らせない この Money
I won't let anyone touch this money!
A million dollars I'd say raise
さあ Come on 覚悟キメて
Now, come on, make up your mind!
震え高ぶる My heart
My heart trembles with excitement!
欲しがるよう じゃね まだ ベイビー
Acting like you want it, you're still a baby!
誰にも負けない
I won't lose to anyone.
感じさせて Love me honey
Make me feel it, love me honey!
あなた内緒だわ
Keep this a secret between us.
ほら 見せてあげる
Here, I'll show you.
秘密って甘いの加減
How sweet a secret can be...
罠を仕かけて 罠にはめるわ
Setting a trap to catch you in it,
油断誘うのよ
luring out your carelessness.
思考を止めたら ジ・エンド
If you stop thinking, it's the end.
何にも知らないような顔で
With a face that acts completely innocent,
落としてあげるわ あなたを
I'll bring you down.
虚勢でしょうそれ You doubt me
You're just bluffing, aren't you? You doubt me.
読み切って レッツ Showdown
Having read your hand, let's showdown!
Deal with the devil 見逃さない
Deal with the devil, I won't miss a thing,
どんな小さなズルだって
no matter how small the trick is.
あたしの目はごまかされないわ
You can't fool my eyes.
A million dollars I'd say raise 勝った相手は
A million dollars, I'd say raise; the opponent I beat,
骨まで愛しつくしてあげる
I'll love them down to the bone.
狙った獲物は逃がさない
I won't let my targeted prey escape,
唇濡らして頂くわ My babe
I'll wet my lips and devour you, my babe.
ダイヤのジャックで手が揃うわ
With the Jack of Diamonds, my hand is complete.
笑みを殺し待つだけ
I just hide my smile and wait.
あたしの中のポーカーフェイスは It's perfect
My poker face is perfect.
一分の隙も見せたりしないわ
I won't show even a fraction of an opening.
視線感じてるわ
I can feel your gaze.
お望みは最後まで
Don't just keep your desires
見てばかりいないで
to yourself until the very end.
あたしと勝負していかない？
Won't you come and play a game with me?
負けるのが怖い？ You're easy game
Afraid of losing? You're easy game.
読み切って レッツ Showdown
Having read your hand, let's showdown!
Deal with the devil 見透かして
Deal with the devil, I'll see right through you
あたしのモノにする
and make you all mine,
あなたの髪の一本まで全部
down to the very last hair on your head.
A million dollars I'd say raise 震えてるわよ 坊や
A million dollars, I'd say raise; you're trembling, boy.
とことんまで行くわ
We're taking this all the way.
Deal with the devil 躊躇わないわ スリル
Deal with the devil, I won't hesitate, this thrill!
誰にも触らせない この Money
I won't let anyone touch this money.
A million dollars I'd say raise さあ Com'on 覚悟キメて
A million dollars, I'd say raise; come on, make up your mind,
灰になるまで打って
and keep betting until we turn to ash!
欲しがるようじゃね まだベイビー
Just wanting it means you're still a baby,
誰にも負けない 感じさせて Love me honey
make me feel like I can't lose to anyone. Love me, honey.
あれ？
Huh?
椅子なくなっちゃった！
The chairs disappeared!
もう少し座らせてほしかった。
I wanted to sit a little bit longer.
はい、みんな！見えてる？聞こえてる？
Hi, everyone! Can you see me? Can you hear me?
ホロライブ所属の癒し系ハーフエルフ、アキロゼことアキ・ローゼンタールです！
I'm Hololive's healing half-elf, Aki Rosenthal, aka AkiRose!
ハロハロハロ、アローナ！
Hallo hallo hallo, Alona!
今回の「アキロゼ生誕祭2026」へようこそ！
Welcome to "AkiRose Birthday Celebration 2026"!
早速ね、なんか色々行われていたんですが、
So right off the bat, a lot of things were happening...
一体今回のライブはどうなっちゃうのか、
I wonder how this live stream is going to turn out!
ぜひ最後まで必見！お見逃しなくお願いします！
Please be sure to watch until the very end, don't miss a thing!
今回のライブのハッシュタグは、
The hashtag for today's live stream is...
#アキロゼ生誕祭2026
#AkiRoseBirthday2026
こちらをつけてXにたくさんポストしてね！
Please use this hashtag and post a lot on X!
もちろん、可愛いスクショ、
Of course, cute screenshots...
えっちなのもたくさん撮って、
and sexy ones too, take plenty of them!
合わせて投稿してください！ライブが終わったら、アキロゼ、見に行きまーす！
Post them together with the hashtag! Once the stream ends, AkiRose will go check them out!
見てね！あ、チャンネル登録もよろしくね！
Check them out, okay? Ah, please subscribe to the channel too!
オッケー？
Okay?
はい、ありがとー！
Alright, thank you!
なんだ？
What is that?
何何何？
What, what, what?
ていうか、ここどこなんだろう？
By the way, where even is this place?
あんなとこにルーレットがある。
There's a roulette wheel over there.
え？回るのかな？
Eh? Will it spin?
回った！えー、すごい！まー、回ったー！
It spun! Woah, amazing! It's spinning!
あ、へえ、何が出んだろう？
Ah, wow, I wonder what will come up?
な、何々？ どうなっちゃうの？
W-What is it? What's going to happen?
ピース？
Peace sign?
え？ 何だ？
Eh? What's this?
(Unhappy?) 悩める人の子よ
(Unhappy?) O suffering child of man
(Unlucky?) 人成らざる者も
(Unlucky?) Even those who aren't human
(Be happy!) 憚らず目指せよ
(Be happy!) Aim without hesitation
(Undead) 生きているんだし
(Undead) After all, you're alive
目を逸らした過去も
The past you turned your eyes from,
退屈な未来も
and the boring future too,
カウンセリング やれやれ
are counseling you. Oh dear, oh dear.
古今東西 ピースピース
All times and places, peace, peace!
(Unhappy? Unlucky? Be happy! Undead)
ねぇねぇ 何だか どうして 戦っているような そんな気がするの
Hey, hey, somehow I feel like I'm fighting against something
触れられない 触れたくもない 過去の自分
Can't touch, don't want to touch, the past self
もうとっくに死んでる 透明な亡霊と対決
Face off against the transparent ghost that died long ago
幼気で痛い記憶の奥
Deep within innocent, painful memories
残念 もう居ないのに
What a shame, even though it's no longer there
あれ？ そっちが良い？ アイロニーね
Huh? You prefer that? How ironic.
透かされているのは現在の自分？
Is it my present self that's being seen through?
ナンセンス 消えないレッテル
Nonsense, a label that won't fade
Yes! 要はコンプレックス
Yes! In short, a complex
取り憑かれているみたい
It's like I'm possessed
巻き付いたまま
Wrapped tight around me,
まだ離れない
it still won't let go,
在りし日の自分
the self of days gone by.
Undead 死んじゃいない
Undead, not dead yet!
お前とお前の連鎖
The chain reaction of you and yourself
生きていることとは 変わり続けることだ
To be alive is to keep changing
不幸に甘んじて 満足するなよ
Don't settle for unhappiness and be satisfied
幸せになろうとしないなんて卑怯だ
Not even trying to be happy is cowardly
この世 この世は
This world, this world is
奇怪 奇怪 ファンタジー
a bizarre, bizarre fantasy.
次は鬼が出るか 蛇が出るか
Will an ogre appear next, or a snake?
出会って 遭って やっと始まる物語
Encountering, facing, the story finally begins!
さあ 人か 化物か
Now, is it a human, or a monster?
閑話休題 ピースピース
Back to the main topic, peace, peace!
Past and future / Can't change the past / Past and future / Run for the future
なんだかどうして 未来になんぞ
Somehow, why is it that in the future,
何の希望もない 期待出来ないような気がして
I feel like there's no hope and nothing to expect?
もう十分生きている 既視感とテンプレで食傷
Lived long enough, sick of déjà vu and cliches
素敵な出来事の気配もない
Not even a sign of something wonderful happening
残念 積んだ経験の因果
Disappointing, the karma of accumulated experience
形骸化された神話と退屈な進化
Hollowed-out myths and boring evolution
要は刺激が欲しいんだ
In short, I just want excitement
飽きちゃった 慣れちゃった
Got bored of it, got used to it
なんて整っていくガイダンス
Such neat and tidy guidance,
増えるコンプライアンス
increasing compliance,
蓋されていくみたい
feels like a lid is being put on.
吸い尽くして
Sucking it dry,
あれも これも どれも 同じ味がする
this, that, all of them taste the same.
Undead 死んじゃいない
Undead, not dead yet!
お前とお前の連鎖
The chain reaction of you and yourself
何時の世も 過去も 未来も 現在にあるんだ
In any era, the past and future are in the present!
生きていることを 愚直に果たせよ
Earnestly fulfill the fact that you are alive
目指せ ハッピーエンド
Aim for a happy ending!
Undead 死んじゃいない
Undead, not dead yet!
お前に言っているんだ
I'm talking to you!
幸せを諦めてしまうな
Don't give up on happiness!
人で在れ
Remain human!
ただ苦しみに慣れて
Just getting used to suffering
耐えているだけじゃ
and enduring it
死んでいるも同然
is no different from being dead,
屍のアンデッド
a corpse of an undead!
(Unhappy?) 悩める人の子よ
(Unhappy?) O suffering child of man
(Unlucky?) 人成らざる者も
(Unlucky?) Even those who aren't human
(Be happy!) 憚らず目指せよ
(Be happy!) Aim without hesitation
(Undead) 生きているんだし
(Undead) After all, you're alive
不幸に浸るも
Soaking in unhappiness,
幸せになるのも
or becoming happy,
そう 全部 全部 お前だ
yeah, it's all, all up to you!
古今東西 一切合切
All times and places, everything altogether
森羅万象 ピースピース
All creation, peace, peace!
Past and future / Can't change the past / Past and future / Run for the future
人の在る 所に いつも憂い事
Where humans exist, there are always worries
生き抜け この化物ばかりの物語
Survive this story full of monsters!
教えてもっと あなたのこと
Tell me more about yourself
(Gimme more, more, more, gimme)
聞かせてもっと あなたの声
Let me hear more of your voice
(Gimme your, your, your, let me)
こんなにドキドキ もう責任取れない
My heart is pounding so much, I can't take responsibility anymore
(Oh I need you, oh I need you)
友達は卒業 運命の私 見つけてほしいな
Graduate from being friends; I want you to find the me of destiny
勇気をだして
Summon your courage!
見つめる作戦
Strategy: stare at you
3つ目 可愛いパワー
Strategy three: cute power!
止められない
I can't stop it!
Yeah Yeah Yeah この恋 この愛で
Yeah, yeah, yeah, with this crush, with this love,
ねえねえ 溶けちゃうよ
Hey, hey, I'm melting!
ねえねえ 気づいて My darling
Hey, hey, notice me, my darling!
届け 大好き
Reach them, my "I love you"!
アイアイ アイスクリーム アイスクリーム 叫びましょう
Love, love, ice cream, ice cream, let's scream it out!
スクリーム アイスクリーム
Scream, ice cream!
アイアイ アイスクリーム アイスクリーム 叫びましょう
Love, love, ice cream, ice cream, let's scream it out!
スクリーム アイスクリーム
Scream, ice cream!
かるびちゃん！
Karubi-chan!
はーい！
Yes!
何が好き？
What do you like?
チョコミント！よりも、あなた！
Mint chocolate chip! ...More than that, you!
ぷるるちゃん！
Pururu-chan!
はーい！
Yes!
何が好き？
What do you like?
ストロベリーフレーバー！よりも、あなた！
Strawberry flavor! ...More than that, you!
アキちゃん！
Aki-chan!
はーい！
Yes!
何が好き？
What do you like?
クッキー＆クリーム！よりも、あなた！
Cookies & Cream! ...More than that, you!
みんな！
Everyone!
はーい！
Yes!
何が好き？
What do you like?
もちろん大好き アイスクリーム！
Of course, we love ice cream!
止められない
I can't stop it!
Yeah Yeah Yeah この恋 この愛で
Yeah, yeah, yeah, with this crush, with this love,
ねえねえ 溶けちゃうよ
Hey, hey, I'm melting!
ねえねえ 気づいて My darling
Hey, hey, notice me, my darling!
届け 大好き
Reach them, my "I love you"!
アイアイ アイスクリーム アイスクリーム 叫びましょう
Love, love, ice cream, ice cream, let's scream it out!
スクリーム アイスクリーム
Scream, ice cream!
アイアイ アイスクリーム アイスクリーム 叫びましょう
Love, love, ice cream, ice cream, let's scream it out!
スクリーム アイスクリーム
Scream, ice cream!
お願い見つけて My darling
Please find me, my darling!
お願い気づいて My darling
Please notice me, my darling!
勇気を出して
Gathering my courage,
近付く作戦
strategy: get closer!
きっかけが増えていく
The chances keep growing and growing!
止められない
I can't stop it!
Yeah Yeah Yeah この恋 この愛で
Yeah, yeah, yeah, with this crush, with this love,
ねえねえ 溶けちゃうよ
Hey, hey, I'm melting!
ねえねえ 気づいて My darling
Hey, hey, notice me, my darling!
それは...
That would be...
あなた！
You!
アイアイ アイスクリーム アイスクリーム 叫びましょう
Love, love, ice cream, ice cream, let's scream it out!
スクリーム アイスクリーム
Scream, ice cream!
アイアイ アイスクリーム アイスクリーム 叫びましょう
Love, love, ice cream, ice cream, let's scream it out!
スクリーム アイスクリーム
Scream, ice cream!
アイアイ アイスクリーム アイスクリーム 叫びましょう
Love, love, ice cream, ice cream, let's scream it out!
スクリーム アイスクリーム
Scream, ice cream!
アイアイ アイスクリーム アイスクリーム 叫びましょう
Love, love, ice cream, ice cream, let's scream it out!
スクリーム アイスクリーム
Scream, ice cream!
La La La...
元気もらえて面白くって、オレンジで、シャンパンコール得意な人居ないかなー？
Is there someone fun, energetic, wearing orange, and great at champagne calls?
それ俺やないかい！
That's totally me!
イケナイ太陽
Naughty Sun
Na Na Na...
ちょっとでいいから 見せてくれないか お前のセクシーフェロモンで 俺 メロメロ
Won't you show me even just a bit? Your sexy pheromones leave me totally head over heels.
AH 触れちゃいそう でも イケナイの？ 徐々に高鳴る鼓動 止められないわ
Ah, I feel like I might touch you, but is that wrong? My fast-beating heart just won't stop.
交わす言葉の...
The words we exchange...
の動きに揺れ動く
...swaying at the movement,
濡れた髪を撫でた
I stroked your wet hair,
そして AH...
and then, ah...
ABC 続かない そんなんじゃダメじゃない
Not continuing past ABC? That won't do!
だって心の奥は違うんじゃない？
Isn't deep inside your heart feeling otherwise?
俺の青春そんなもんじゃない 熱く奥で果てたいよ
My youth isn't so mild; I want to burn out deep inside.
きっと君じゃなきゃヤダよ
It definitely has to be you, or I don't want it!
俺はイケナイ太陽
I'm the bad sun.
赤い糸なんて絵空事でも 下心でさえ信じたいの
Even if the "red thread" is a dream, I want to believe even in ulterior motives.
俺は正しい君も正しい とにかくもう左右されないぜ
I'm right, you're right too; anyway, I won't be swayed anymore!
騙し騙され胸うずく 下手な芝居がより盛り上げる夜
Deceiving and being deceived, my heart aches; clumsy acting hypes up the night.
息が耳に触れた二人 AH
The two of us, breath touching our ears, ah!
ABC 続かない そんなんじゃダメじゃない
Not continuing past ABC? That won't do!
だって心の奥は違うんじゃない？
Isn't deep inside your heart feeling otherwise?
私の青春そんなもんじゃない 熱く奥で果てたいよ
My youth isn't so mild; I want to burn out deep inside.
きっと君じゃなきゃヤダよ
It definitely has to be you, or I don't want it!
私イケナイ太陽
I'm the bad sun.
交わす言葉の記憶遠く 口元の動きに揺れ動く
Memories of exchanged words fade far off, swaying at the movement of lips.
濡れた髪を撫でた そして AH...
I stroked your wet hair, and then, ah...
ABC...
ABC 続かない そんなんじゃダメじゃない
Not continuing past ABC? That won't do!
だって心の奥は違うんじゃない？
Isn't deep inside your heart feeling otherwise?
俺の青春そんなもんじゃない 熱く奥で果てたいよ
My youth isn't so mild; I want to burn out deep inside.
きっと君じゃなきゃヤダよ
It definitely has to be you, or I don't want it!
俺はイケナイ太陽
I'm the bad sun.
絡み合う糸は君と俺を
The intertwining threads bind you and me,
結ぶ赤い糸
a binding red thread of fate.
みんな...
Everyone...
来てくれて...
...for coming!
ありがとうー！
Thank you so much!
ということで、お友達が来てくれたので、せっかくなので自己紹介してもらいたいと思います！まずはPururuちゃんから！
So, since my friends came over, I'd like them to introduce themselves! First up, Pururu-chan!
はーい！
Yay!
天使と悪魔のぷるぷるエンジェルデビル、甘路ぷるるでーす！
I'm the angel and devil, Purupuru Angel-Devil, Amaji Pururu!
アキちゃん！お誕生日おめでとうー！
Aki-chan! Happy birthday!
ありがとう〜！
Thank you~!
いやー、めっちゃ楽しかったねー！ありがとう！
Wow, that was so much fun! Thank you!
はーい！続いてかるびちゃんー！
Alright! Next is Karubi-chan~!
はい！お肉の国のお姫様、赤見かるびでーす！
Hi! Princess from Meat Kingdom, Akami Karubi here!
アキのせ！誕生日おめでとう！
Akinose! Happy birthday!
ありがとうー！
Thank you~!
ライブって、友達とのライブ初めてだからさ、マジで嬉しかったよ！呼んでくれてありがとうね！
This is my first time doing a live concert with friends, so I was really happy! Thanks for inviting me!
またやろうね！
Let's do this again!
また行こう！ありがとー！
Let me come again! Thank you~!
素晴らしい！
Wonderful!
そして最後にズズさん！
And finally, Zuzu-san!
はい！僕のこと知らない人いると思うんで、自己紹介だけさせてください！
Yes! I think some people might not know me, so please let me introduce myself!
来たー！
Here he comes!
雨降ってザーザー、少女時代はGee! Gee!
Rain pouring down zaa-zaa, Girls' Generation goes Gee! Gee!
俺の名前はズズズズズッ、ズズでございます！
My name is Zu-zu-zu-zu-zut, Zuzu!
いやー！お誕生日おめでとうー！
Yeah! Happy birthday!
ありがとうー！
Thank you~!
疲れたー！疲れたね！
I'm so tired! That was exhausting!
あ、速い！
Ah, so fast!
おい、忙しい人気者だ！
Hey, you're a busy, popular person!
気をつけて！大丈夫？
Be careful! Are you okay?
ありがとう！
Thank you!
アロムちゃん、アルムちゃん、ありがとー！
Arome-chan, Arume-chan, thank you!
あー、賑やかで楽しかったー！
Ah, that was so lively and fun!
まるでこの世界で
It feels like in this world,
二人だけみたいだね
it's just the two of us.
なんて少しだけ
I just let myself
夢を見てしまっただけ
dream a little bit.
つま先に月明かり
Moonlight on my toes,
花束の香り
the scent of a bouquet,
指に触れる指
fingers touching fingers.
さよなら もう行かなきゃ
Goodbye, I have to go now,
何もかも忘れて
and forget everything.
硝子の上を 裸足のまま歩く
Walking barefoot on glass,
痛むごとに 血が流れて落ちていく
with every step, blood flows and drips away.
お願い その赤い足跡を辿って 会いにきて
Please, follow those red footprints, come find me.
錆びたPOOLに放たれていく金魚
Goldfish released into a rusty pool,
靴箱の中隠した林檎
an apple hidden in the shoe locker,
萎びた君の肌に残る傷痕
scars left on your withered skin,
犬のように泳いだ迷子
a lost child swimming like a dog.
どこにいるの (ここにいるよ)
Where are you? (I'm right here.)
何をしているの (ずっと見てるよ)
What are you doing? (I'm always watching you.)
この世を間違いで満たそう
Let's fill this world with mistakes.
側にいてよ 遊びに行こうよ
Stay by my side, let's go have some fun.
どこにいるの
Where are you?
硝子の上を 裸足のまま歩く
Walking barefoot on glass,
痛むごとに 血が流れて落ちていく
with every step, blood flows and drips away.
お願い その赤い足跡を辿って 会いにきて
Please, follow those red footprints, come find me.
まるでこの世界で
It feels like in this world,
二人だけみたいだね
it's just the two of us.
なんて少しだけ
I just let myself
夢を見てしまっただけ
dream a little bit.
さあ、選択の時だ。
Now, it is time to make a choice.
コイン
A coin.
このコインは...
This coin is...
そうか
I see.
君はそっちなんだね
So you're on that side.
そっち？
That side?
ここに座って
Sit down here.
えっ？
Huh?
この後は君次第だよ
What happens next is up to you.
Whisper Whisper Whisper
忘れられないのは この目のせい
The reason I can't forget is because of these eyes.
赤く残る過ち 甘噛みの跡
Red mistakes left behind, traces of sweet nibbles.
これですれ違い
Passing by each other like this,
止め処もない
with no end in sight.
誰もいない愛着に
Attachment where no one exists,
悪魔を探す
searching for the devil.
作り笑いは この耳のせい
The fake smile is because of these ears.
深い風の中から
From deep within the wind,
呼びかける声
a calling voice.
Whisper Whisper Whisper まだ触らせない
Whisper Whisper Whisper, I won't let you touch me yet.
この檻を抜け出して
Escaping from this cage,
悪魔は賭ける
the devil makes a bet.
鏡の前で この口のせい
In front of the mirror, because of this mouth,
伝えたい言葉さえ
even the words I want to say,
噛み殺す夜
a night where I choke them down.
Whisper Whisper Whisper まだ打ち明けない
Whisper Whisper Whisper, I won't reveal it yet.
神様を裏切って
Betraying God,
悪魔と過ごす
spending time with the devil.
曖昧 夢を見ていたい あなたに
To you, who wants to keep dreaming vaguely,
そっと 気づかせてあげたいだけ
I just want to gently make you realize.
ああ あなたにも
Ah, to you as well.
消えない傷を隠したい あなたに
To you, who wants to hide unhealing wounds,
そっと 悩ませてあげたいだけ
I just want to gently give you something to ponder.
ああ あなたにも
Ah, to you as well.
悪魔を探す
Searching for the devil.
作り笑いは この耳のせい
The fake smile is because of these ears.
深い風の中から
From deep within the wind,
呼びかける声
a calling voice.
Whisper Whisper Whisper まだ触らせない
Whisper Whisper Whisper, I won't let you touch me yet.
この檻を抜け出して
Escaping from this cage,
悪魔は賭ける
the devil makes a bet.
鏡の前で この口のせい
In front of the mirror, because of this mouth,
伝えたい言葉さえ
even the words I want to say,
噛み殺す夜
a night where I choke them down.
Whisper Whisper Whisper まだ打ち明けない
Whisper Whisper Whisper, I won't reveal it yet.
神様を裏切って
Betraying God,
悪魔と過ごす
spending time with the devil.
BANG!!!
イイ気 嫌い 都市気 愛憎劇 ふっとでBANG
Smugness, hatred, urban vibes, drama... gone with a BANG!
かかって来い maturity
Come at me, maturity.
私に負けはなし
There's no losing for me.
ここまでって言われて
Told "that's as far as you go,"
その場を出たら負け
but leaving that spot means losing.
あの日乗り越えたweekdays
Those weekdays I pushed through back then,
強くなった
I've grown stronger.
足跡はライトアップされたかのように
It's as if my footsteps are lit up in the spotlight.
言いたいことは言う
I say what I want to say.
やりたくないことはしない
I don't do what I don't want to do.
悪意 気にしない
Malice? I don't care.
みんな違うの当然だし
It's only natural that everyone is different.
私 変わらないけど前の自分
I haven't changed, but compared to my past self...
Everybody say I want to be free
本音を言わない それじゃ何も変えられない
Not speaking your true feelings won't change a thing.
I want to be free
描いた自分像で
As the image of myself I envisioned,
生きてるんだ私
that is how I am living!
That is how I am living!
声を上げて
Raise your voice!
生まれた時から選んだ決断
The decisions chosen ever since I was born,
思いのせ 私の姿
carrying my feelings, this is who I am.
他人のことなんて 何一つ関係ない
What others do has nothing to do with me.
誇れ 自分に
Take pride in yourself!
イイ気 嫌い 都市気 愛憎劇 ふっとでBANG
Smugness, hatred, urban vibes, drama... gone with a BANG!
ソウル鳴らせ
Sound your soul!
てかこのリリックかませ
Like, hit 'em with these lyrics!
分からす 挑発
Show them what's up, provoke them,
舌巻いて舌打ちからの
roll your tongue, click your tongue, and then...
Excuse me? 悪からず 倍返し喰らい
Excuse me? No hard feelings, take double the payback!
地雷 聴かせてあげる Ah
I'll let you hear the landmine, ah
You can't like I'm quiet now
私についているから
Because I'm right here with you
Everybody say, I want to be free
このビート 衆人完全黙らせる Show
This beat will completely silence the crowd in this show
Everybody say Ah...
目覚めさせてあげる
I'll awaken you
Wake up, wake up, It's time to dash!
ねぇ 聴いてよ Dash!
Hey, listen up, dash!
生まれたその時から選んできたんだ 思い出せ
We've been making choices since the day we were born, remember
私は私だ
I am who I am
不可能なことなど何ひとつもないさ じゃないの
There's not a single impossible thing, isn't that right?
生まれたその時から選んできたんだ 思い出せ
You've been making choices since the day you were born, remember
あなたはあなただ
You are who you are
不可能なことなど何ひとつもないさ じゃないの
There's not a single impossible thing, isn't that right?
一杯 自分に！
Fill yourself up!
See! Like, JUST EAT! I don't care, フトペパン!
See! Like, JUST EAT! I don't care, futopepan!
Against, See! Like, JUST EAT! I don't care, フトペパン!
Against, See! Like, JUST EAT! I don't care, futopepan!
Bad Apple!!
[Title: Bad Apple!!]
流れゆく時の中ででも
Even within the flow of passing time,
気だるさがほらグルグル廻って
a feeling of languor spins around and around.
私から離れる心も見えないわ
I can't even see my heart straying away from me.
そう知らんない
Yes, I just don't know.
自分から動くこともなく
Without moving of my own accord,
時の隙間に流され続けて
I keep drifting through the gaps in time.
知らないわ周りのことなど
I don't care about anything around me,
私は私それだけ
I am just me, and that's all.
夢見てる何も見てない
Dreaming, yet seeing nothing at all,
語るも無駄な自分の言葉
my own words are useless to speak.
悲しむなんて疲れるだけよ
Feeling sad only wears me out,
何も感じず過ごせばいいの
so it's better to live without feeling anything.
戸惑う言葉与えられても
Even when given confusing words,
自分の心ただ上の空
my mind remains completely absent.
もし私から動くのならば
If I were to make a move myself,
すべて変えるのなら黒にする
if I were to change everything, I'd paint it black.
こんな自分に未来はあるの？
Is there a future for someone like me?
こんな世界に私はいるの？
Do I even belong in a world like this?
今切ないの？今悲しいの？
Am I in pain right now? Am I sad right now?
自分のことも解らないまま
Without even understanding myself,
歩むことさえ疲れるだけよ
even walking forward just exhausts me.
人のことなど知りもしないわ
I don't know or care about anyone else.
こんな私もし変われるのなら
If even someone like me could change,
もし変われるのなら白になる
if I could change, I would become white.
流れゆく時の中ででも
Even within the flow of passing time,
気だるさがほらグルグル廻って
a feeling of languor spins around and around.
私から離れる心も見えないわ
I can't even see my heart straying away from me.
そう知らんない
Yes, I just don't know.
自分から動くこともなく
Without moving of my own accord,
時の隙間に流され続けて
I keep drifting through the gaps in time.
知らないわ周りのことなど
I don't care about anything around me,
私は私それだけ
I am just me, and that's all.
夢見てる何も見てない
Dreaming, yet seeing nothing at all,
語るも無駄な自分の言葉
my own words are useless to speak.
悲しむなんて疲れるだけよ
Feeling sad only wears me out.
悲しむなんて 疲れるだけよ
Being sad is just exhausting.
何も感じず過ごせばいいの
I should just live without feeling anything.
戸惑う言葉与えられても
Even if I'm given confusing words,
自分の心ただ上の空
my heart is just somewhere else.
もし私から動くのならば
If I were to move on my own,
すべて変えるのなら黒にする
if I were to change everything, I'd make it black.
動くのならば
If I move,
if I move,
すべて壊すわ
I'll destroy everything,
I'll destroy everything.
悲しむならば
If I am to grieve,
if I am to grieve,
私の心
can my heart
白く変われる？
turn white?
あなたのことも
About you,
私のことも
about me,
すべてのことも
about everything,
まだ知らないの
I still don't know.
重い瞼を
If I open
開けたのならば
my heavy eyelids,
すべて壊すの
if everything is to be destroyed,
なら黒になれ
then turn to black!
いつか君が瞳に灯す愛の光が
Someday, the light of love you kindle in your eyes
時を超えて
will transcend time,
滅び急ぐ世界の夢を 確かに一つ壊すだろう
and surely destroy one dream of a world hurrying to ruin.
躊躇いを飲み干して
Swallow down your hesitation.
君が望むモノは何？
What is it that you desire?
こんな欲深い憧れの行方に
On the path of such greedy longing,
儚い明日はあるの？
is there a fleeting tomorrow?
子供の頃夢に見てた 古の魔法のように
Like the ancient magic I dreamed of as a child,
闇さえ砕く力で
with power that can shatter even darkness,
微笑む君に会いたい
I want to meet you smiling.
怯えるこの手の中には
In these trembling hands,
手折られた花の勇気
is the courage of a plucked flower.
想いだけが頼る全て
My feelings alone are all I rely on,
光を呼び覚ます
awakening the light...
願い
...my wish.
いつか君も誰かの為に 強い力を望むのだろう
Someday, you too will desire great power for someone's sake, won't you?
愛が胸を捕らえた夜に
On the night when love captures your heart,
未知の言葉が生まれてくる
unknown words will be born.
迷わずに行けるなら
If I can go without hesitation,
心が砕けてもいいわ
I don't mind if my heart breaks into pieces.
いつも目の前の悲しみに
To face the sorrow always before my eyes,
立ち向かう為の呪文が欲しい
I want a spell.
君はまだ夢見る記憶
You are still a memory dreaming,
私は眠らない明日
I am the sleepless tomorrow.
二人が出会う奇跡を
To seize the miracle of our meeting,
勝ち取る為に進むわ
I will press forward.
怯えるこの手の中には
In these trembling hands,
手折られた花の刃
is the blade of a plucked flower.
想いだけが生きる全て
My feelings alone are all that live,
心に振りかざす
brandished in my heart...
願い
...my wish.
囚われた太陽の
Illuminated by captive suns,
輝く
shining...
不思議の国の本が好きだった頃
back when I used to like books about strange lands,
願いはきっと叶うと
I believed the fairy tales
教えてくれたお伽話を
that taught us that wishes
信じた
would surely come true.
光と影の
Among the light and shadow...
中...
within...
静かに咲き乱れていた
Gently, blooming wildly in silence,
古の魔法 優しく
the ancient magic gently...
世界を変える力が
"The power to change the world
その手にあると囁く
lies in those hands of yours," it whispers.
終わらない夢を見よう
Let us have an unending dream.
君と行く時の中で
During this time I go through with you,
想いだけが生きる全て
my feelings alone are all that I live for.
命を作るのは
What creates my life
願い...
is this wish...
うわー！
Whoa!
アキちゃん、お誕生日おめでとう！
Aki-chan, happy birthday!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
今日は来てくれてありがとうございます！
Thank you so much for coming today!
こちらこそですよ！呼んでくれてありがとう！
Likewise! Thank you for inviting us!
実はね、二人を呼んだのちょっと理由があって
Actually, there's a reason I invited you two today.
おっ、何だ何だ？
Oh? What is it?
前にアキロゼの4周年の時に3人でKalafinaさんの曲を歌わせてもらったんだけど
Back during AkiRose's 4th Anniversary, the three of us sang a Kalafina song together, right?
やりましたね！めっちゃ良かったやつね！
We did! It was so awesome!
ハーモニーがね！
The harmonies, right!
もうね、ミオちゃんの歌も大好きだし、ロボ子さんの歌も大好きだし、もう忘れられないの！
I loved Mio-chan's singing so much, and I loved Roboco-san's singing so much too, I just couldn't forget it!
わかる、わかる！
I get it, I get it!
だからもう一回、ライブステージで3人で歌いたくて、今日は来ていただきました！
So I wanted us three to sing on a live stage together once again, which is why I asked you to come today!
嬉しい！ありがとう！
I'm so happy! Thank you!
だからこれから、これを機に、もっと3人で歌ったりとか…
So taking this opportunity, doing more things like singing as a trio...
なんかそういうの挑戦できたら、めっちゃ嬉しいね！
...or taking on challenges like that would make me so happy!
いいですか？ハーモニーを重ねていきましょうよ！
Is that okay? Let's keep layering our harmonies together!
えー、いいの！？
Eh, really?!
ユニット名とか欲しいな！
I want a unit name or something!
確かに！え、何ならちょっと世界目指せるぐらいの3人だから…
Indeed! I mean, with the three of us, we could even aim for the world...
世界のコンサートをしようよ！
Let's do a world concert tour!
したい、したい！世界に轟く…！
I want to! Resonating across the world...!
何かをね、したいということで！
We want to do something like that!
この3人でライブとか、アコースティックとか、オーケストラライブとか！
Like a live show with the three of us, or acoustic, or an orchestra live!
えー、良くないですか！？我らならできるかもしれない！
Wouldn't that be great?! With us, we might actually be able to do it!
お願いしまーす！
Please!
あれ？これは一体何ですか？
Huh? What in the world is this?
もしかして、このライブでみんなからの…
Could it be that, from everyone during this live...
なんかいいパワーで…
...some kind of great power...
こちらがなんと、完成しました！
...this has actually been completed!
イエーイ！何だそれ！
Yay! What is that?!
実はこの後、アキロゼの新曲が出ます！
Actually, after this, AkiRose's new song will be released!
やったー！出たー！
Yay! It's out!
こちら、今回のライブのテーマというか、壮大なテーマがあるんですけれども
This track embodies the theme—or rather, the grand theme—of today's live stream,
そちらがつまったような楽曲になっています！
packed right into a single song!
そしてライブ終わりの日付が変わる時にリリースしますので、ぜひ聴いてください！
And it will be released when the date changes after this live stream ends, so please listen to it!
聴くぞー！ハイ！
We'll listen! Yay!
ではでは、次の曲に行きますか！
Well then, shall we move on to the next song?
次の曲？新曲のお披露目！
The next song? The reveal of the new song!
なんだってー！？しちゃいます！
What?! We're going to do it!
今から！？今から頑張ります！最後まで見逃せないですね！
Starting now?! Starting now, I'll do my best! You can't miss a single second until the end!
アキちゃん、頑張ってね！ありがとー！
Aki-chan, good luck! Thank you!
魅惑の言葉の裏面に忍ばせた
Hidden behind the alluring words
1mgのスパイス
Is 1mg of spice.
たちまち華麗な指先で彩る
Instantly colored by splendid fingertips,
本日のダイス
Are today's dice.
辺り見て妥協してっちゃ生き残れないでしょう
Looking around and compromising won't let you survive, right?
率直に言ってそう全てが欲しい
To be frank, yes, I want it all!
一人勝ちにオールイン
Going all-in for the solo victory.
どうなっちゃってもいいじゃない 限界なんてないじゃない
Who cares what happens? There are no limits anyway, right?
翻弄して 翻弄されて ゾ・ク・ゾ・ク
Toying with others, being toyed with—gives me thrills and chills.
喰らっちゃっても本懐でしょ 最低だって滾るでしょ
Even if I'm consumed, it's what I wanted; even if it's the worst, it boils my blood, right?
見透かして 見透かされて 故に
Seeing through, being seen through, and therefore...
終わりは無い
...there is no end.
高鳴るこの全てノンフィクション
All of this pounding thrill is non-fiction.
嗜むはずでもたまには飲みすぎて1回休み
I meant to just savor it, but sometimes I drink too much and lose a turn.
周りもザワつく思わぬうたた寝で2回休み
The crowd stirs as an unexpected nap costs me two turns.
切れる頭と勘だけじゃ手に入らないモノ
Things you can't get with just a sharp mind and intuition.
速攻で逝って満たされるならいい
If going out in a quick blitz satisfies me, then so be it.
命懸けで楽しむわ
I'll enjoy this with my life on the line.
天と地は案外近いのぃ 「この通り」 命乞い？
Heaven and earth are surprisingly close. "Like this"—begging for mercy?
たかがモノポリー されど王女に 秘める想いで今宵も私は強い
It's just Monopoly, yet with feelings hidden as a princess, I'm strong tonight too.
どうなっちゃってもいいじゃない 限界なんてないじゃない
Who cares what happens? There are no limits anyway, right?
翻弄して 翻弄されて ゾ・ク・ゾ・ク
Toying with others, being toyed with—gives me thrills and chills.
喰らっちゃっても本懐でしょ 最低だって滾るでしょ
Even if I'm consumed, it's what I wanted; even if it's the worst, it boils my blood, right?
見透かして 見透かされて 故に
Seeing through, being seen through, and therefore...
終わりは無い
...there is no end.
高鳴るこの全てノンフィクション
All of this pounding thrill is non-fiction.
堕ちても昇ってもノンフィクション！
Whether falling or ascending, it's non-fiction!
中川に浮かぶ 夕日をめがけて
Aiming at the setting sun floating over the Naka River,
小石を蹴ったら 靴まで飛んで
I kicked a pebble and my shoe flew off too.
ジョギングしていた 大工の頭領に
The carpenter boss out for a jog
ガキのまんまだい と笑われたのさ
Laughed at me, saying "You're still just a kid!"
どこかに元気を 落っことしても
Even if I lose my high spirits somewhere,
葛飾亀有 アクビをひとつ
Here in Kameari, Katsushika, with a single yawn,
変わらない街並みが 妙にやさしいよ
The unchanging townscape feels strangely comforting.
中央広場で 子供の手を引く
In the central plaza, holding her child's hand,
太ったあの娘は 初恋の彼女
That plump woman was my first love.
権八池で 渡したラブレター
The love letter I gave her at Gonpachi Pond,
今も持ってると からかわれたよ
She teased me, saying she still has it.
何にもいいこと なかったけど
Nothing good really happened today, but
葛飾水元 流れる雲と
Here in Mizumoto, Katsushika, with the drifting clouds,
ラプソディー口ずさみ 少し歩こうか
Humming a rhapsody, shall I walk a little while?
カラスが鳴くから もう日が暮れるね
The crows are cawing, so the sun must be setting.
焼き鳥ほおばり ビール飲もうか
Shall I munch on yakitori and drink a beer?
トンガリ帽子の 取水塔から
From the intake tower shaped like a pointed hat,
帝釈天へと 夕陽が落ちる
The evening sun sets towards Taishakuten.
明日もこうして 終わるんだね
Tomorrow will probably end just like this too.
葛飾柴又 倖せだって
Here in Shibamata, Katsushika, this too is happiness.
明日もこうして 終わるんだね
Tomorrow will end like this too, won't it?
葛飾柴又 幸せだって
Katsushika Shibamata, saying "I'm happy",
なくして気がついた
I realized after losing it,
バカな俺だから
because I'm such a fool.
どこかに元気を 落っことしても
Even if I lose my spirit somewhere,
葛飾亀有 あくびをひとつ
Katsushika Kameari, giving a single yawn,
変わらない町並みが
the unchanging townscape
妙にやさしいよ
is strangely gentle.
アキロゼ生誕祭2026をご覧の皆さん、いかがでしたでしょうかー！
To everyone watching Aki Rose Birthday 2026, how was it?!
さーて、ここからは大事なお知らせがあるので、最後までしっかり聞いていってね！
Now then, there are important announcements from here, so listen carefully until the end!
まずはお知らせ1つ目！アキロゼ生誕祭2026誕生日グッズ発売でーす！
First, announcement number 1! Aki Rose Birthday 2026 Birthday Goods are now on sale!
今回はライブの世界観をぎゅっと楽しんでもらえるグッズを頑張って制作いたしました！
This time, we worked hard to create merch that lets you fully enjoy the worldview of the live concert!
なので、今回のライブが良かったなーって思った方はぜひ応援で購入していただくのもすごく嬉しいです！
So if you thought this live concert was great, I'd be super happy if you purchased them to support me!
それでは、まず1つ目のグッズ！「Life is GAME ラバーマット」！
Now then, first merch item! "Life is GAME Rubber Mat"!
今回のイラストはLAM先生に描き下ろしていただきました！素敵なイラストありがとうございます！
The illustration this time was newly drawn by LAM-sensei! Thank you so much for the wonderful illustration!
今回のライブの世界観をイメージしたイラストになっています！めちゃくちゃセクシーで色っぽいけどかっこいいようなアキロゼになっています！
It's themed after the worldview of this live concert! It's an Aki Rose that's super sexy and alluring, yet cool!
ラバーマットで思う存分楽しんでください！
Please enjoy it to your heart's content on this rubber mat!
ちなみにサイズはカードゲームにぴったり！この意味、分かるよね？
By the way, the size is perfect for card games! You get what this means, right?
2つ目のグッズが、「運命の5枚 タロット風アクリルスタンドセット」！
The second item is "5 Cards of Fate Tarot-style Acrylic Stand Set"!
アキロゼがあなたのことを占って背中を押してあげます！
Aki Rose will divine your fortune and encourage you!
1日の始まりや何か運命を託したいみたいなそんなときに、使って楽しむ、
At the start of your day, or when you want to entrust something to fate, you can use it...
そして5枚バーンって飾っておけるので、見ても楽しめるようになっております！
and you can display all 5 cards prominently, so it's also fun to look at!
占い方法は、この後紹介するアキロゼのASMRボイスと連動しております！
The fortune-telling method is linked with Aki Rose's ASMR voice pack that I'll introduce next!
飾っても楽しい、使っても楽しい、そのような連動グッズになっているのでぜひGETしてください！
It's a linked item that's fun to display and fun to use, so please get it!
続いてのグッズは、「アキロゼのトランプ」！作っちゃいましたー！
Next up is "Aki Rose's Playing Cards"! We actually made them!
こちら、実際に遊んでいただけるトランプなので、たくさん予備も買ったほうがいいんじゃないかなーと思います！
These are real playing cards you can actually play with, so I think buying lots of spares might be a good idea!
ぜひトランプでもアキロゼをたくさん楽しんでアピールもしてくださいね！
Please enjoy Aki Rose through playing cards and show them off to others too!
続いてはこちら、「アキロゼのカードケース」！
Next up is this: "Aki Rose's Card Case"!
ホロカはもちろん、トランプなど小物入れを入れても大丈夫です！ぜひお家や持ち歩きに使ってね！
Of course for Holoca, but it's also great for holding small items like playing cards! Please use it at home or on the go!
そしてボイスの紹介です！今回もASMRボイスを特別に発売！
And now for the voice packs! This time, we're releasing special ASMR voice packs again!
アキとロゼがそれぞれ左右からあなたのことを誘惑しちゃうかも？
Aki and Rose might tempt you from the left and right respectively!
台本も頑張って書いたので、ぜひぜひたっぷり楽しんでもらえたら嬉しいです！
I worked hard writing the script, so I'd be super glad if you enjoy it to the fullest!
こちらボイスは『Life is GAME ～アキロゼの盤上～』こちらをメインとし、
For these voice packs, "Life is GAME ~Aki Rose's Board~" is the main track,
ASMRショートボイスとして先ほどの「運命の5枚 タロット風アクリルスタンド」と連動したショートボイスが入っております！
and as ASMR short voices, there are short voices linked to the "5 Cards of Fate Tarot-style Acrylic Stands"!
ショートボイスのシャッフル・ランダム再生をして、選ばれたボイスがあなたの運命の1枚になります！
By playing the short voices on shuffle or random playback, the selected voice becomes your card of fate!
ぜひ色々楽しんでね！
Please enjoy them in various ways!
これからのグッズ全てが詰まったフルセット購入には、なんと特典もついております！
Purchasing the full set containing all these merch items comes with a bonus!
今回のキービジュアルのイラストを使ったチケット風カードになっております！
It's a ticket-style card featuring the key visual illustration!
あなたはこのゲームに参加する？参加したい？こちらもライブの世界観を高めるアイテムになっているのでぜひGETしてください！
Will you participate in this game? Do you want to join? This is also an item that enhances the live concert experience, so please get it!
そして数量限定版あります！直筆サインとメッセージ入りチケット風カードになっております！頑張って書きます！
And there's a limited quantity version! It comes with a hand-written signature and message on the ticket-style card! I'll do my best writing them!
そして数量限定版が終わり次第、箔押しでの複製サインとメッセージが入ったチケット風カードになります！ぜひフルセット購入特典GETしてね！
And once the limited quantity version sells out, it will be a ticket-style card with foil-stamped replicated signature and message! Make sure to get the full set bonus!
大事な発売時間は、この後21時30分！21時30分にショップオープンです！
The important release time is today at 21:30! The shop opens at 21:30!
ぜひ登録など準備して備えておいてね！
Please make preparations like registering in advance and be ready!
続きましてお知らせ2つ目！
Moving on to announcement number 2!
この後21時45分からメンバー限定のアフターライブをお送りします！
Starting from 21:45 today, we will be hosting a members-only After Live!
ライブ本編とはまた違う楽曲を披露する予定なので、ぜひお楽しみに！
We plan to perform songs that are different from the main live concert, so please look forward to it!
今日メンバーになった方もぜひぜひ見てね！
Anyone who became a member today, please check it out too!
ちなみに過去のライブのメンバー限定アフター...
By the way, for past lives' members-only after...
アフターライブも見れちゃうと思うので
I think you'll also be able to watch the after-live,
ぜひそのあたりも見てもてねー
so please be sure to check that out as well!
ちなみに今回のサムネイラストは
By the way, this time's thumbnail illustration
メンバー限定で壁紙として
will be given out as a wallpaper
プレゼント予定です！
exclusively to members!
お楽しみに！
Look forward to it!
そして！
And next...
お知らせ3つ目！
The third announcement!
本日の生誕祭ライブの後も
Even after today's Birthday Live...
お楽しみはまだまだ続きます！
the fun is far from over!
なんと！ホロアースにて
Believe it or not, in HoloEarth,
特別企画！
a special event:
アキ・ローゼンタール生誕祭2026 アンコール in ホロアース
"Aki Rosenthal Birthday Fest 2026 Encore in HoloEarth"
を開催しまーす！
will be held!
今回初披露した
I'll be singing my new song,
新曲『モノポリー』をホロアースで歌っちゃいます！
"Monopoly", which was performed for the first time today, in HoloEarth!
いろんな角度からアキロゼのパフォーマンスや
You can closely watch AkiRose's performance
演出をじっくりと見てみてくださいね！
and stage effects from all kinds of angles!
さらにホロアースだけのMCパートも
Plus, there'll be a generous MC segment
たっぷりやるので
exclusive to HoloEarth,
ぜひぜひ会いに来てください！
so please come see me!
開催日は3月13日、3月13日です！
The date is March 13th, March 13th!
詳細はホロアース公式Xをチェックしてね！
Check the official HoloEarth X account for details!
そして最後のお知らせが
And our final announcement...
新曲『モノポリー』！
My new song, "Monopoly"!
本日日付が変わる頃にリリースされますので
It'll be released around midnight today,
各音楽配信サービスから
so please buy and stream it
ぜひ購入してね！たくさん聴いてね！
on all streaming services! Give it lots of listens!
振付も歌もとってもキャッチーなので
Both the choreography and song are super catchy,
覚えてみんなで楽しんでもらえる
so I hope you learn it and enjoy it together,
愛されるような楽曲になってくれたら嬉しいなって思っています！
and that it becomes a beloved track for everyone!
また後日ライブ配信で
Also, in a future stream,
新曲『モノポリー』だったり
I'd like to talk about the new song "Monopoly,"
今回のライブに触れた後日談などを語ったり
share behind-the-scenes stories about today's live,
一緒に見たりなどしたいなと思ってるので
or watch it together with you all,
ぜひチャンネル登録、高評価ぽちっ
so please subscribe to the channel, smash that like button,
通知もオン！してなかった人は今ぽちっとね！
and turn on notifications! If you haven't, hit that button now!
絶対絶対また会いに来てね！
Definitely, definitely come see me again!
それでは...
And now...
運命は時に残酷。
Fate is sometimes cruel.
あなたが選びたくて選んだものではないかもしれない。
It may not be something you wanted to choose.
だけど...
But...
いつでもあなたの人生は...あなたのもの。
your life is always... yours.
人生は一度きり。
You only live once.
やり直しのきかないこのゲーム、
In this game where there are no retries,
あなたはどう楽しむ？
how will you enjoy it?